

Aaron Walker

12 Wensleydale Avenue, Leyburn, North Yorkshire, DL8 5SD.



aaron45587@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/aaron-james-walker

Personal Profile

I am currently a student studying Computer Science at Teesside University with a predicted 1st class degree. I have industry experience in the form of a placement year working as a software developer at Accenture. I am a hardworking individual who enjoys problem solving and working as an effective team player. My University modules have helped me develop strong mathematical skills as well as gaining significant technical experience with both hardware and software. My previous work experience has equipped me with an excellent attention to detail along with great organisational skills.

Education

2015 - Present: Teesside University, Working towards a BSc in Computer Science

Achievements: Presented with an award for "Outstanding entrepreneurial skills"

First year modules: Average grade: 74.5% Second year modules: Average grade: 68.2%

Placement year: Grade: 85%

Third year modules currently studying:

- Artificial Intelligence Applications
- Software Architecture
- Advanced Database Design

- **Embedded Systems**
- Final Year Project

2013-2015: Queen Elizabeth Sixth Form College

3 Advanced levels: Graphic Design (C), IT Double Award, Two Advanced Levels at (B, C).

2007-2012: The Wensleydale School and Sixth Form

8 GCSEs from grades C-A including Mathematics (B), English (B) and Information Technology (Distinction).

Employment

June 2017 - August 2018: Accenture

Software Developer

For my placement year at University I joined Accenture as a software developer. Upon joining the company, I completed many kinds of training in both technical development skills and soft skills. I spent my placement within an award-winning team specialising in robotic process automation for the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP). During my time on this team, I have demonstrated my skills working in an agile development environment and have successfully taken multiple RPA products to production in addition to a machine learning solution to help increase success rates of 1 process from 45% to 90% and over. The technology I worked with on a regular basis included C# and VB.NET. I also used Python, C++ and HTML/CSS in other projects throughout the year.

August 2016 - September 2016: North Yorkshire County Council, County Hall, Northallerton. IT Undergraduate Placement

I joined North Yorkshire County Council on a 6 week internship as part of their 2020 program. There, I was tasked with working as part of a team to set up new machines for employees at NYCC. As part of this process I attended rollout sessions where I was tasked with handing out the new equipment to the end user and explaining to the user how to use the equipment effectively. I was also tasked with fixing hardware issues and taking a company car to deliver new equipment to external offices.

June 2011 - Present: Leyburn Bikes, Leyburn, North Yorkshire. Shop Keeper and Cycle Mechanic.

Working at Leyburn Bikes has provided me with a variety of responsibilities. These include opening the business at the beginning of the day, along with closing and locking the premises at the end of the day. As a contrast to my work at the Bolton Arms and Three Horseshoes, much of my time at Leyburn bikes is spent working independently, carrying out tasks such as equipping customers with specialist information regarding bicycle components and complete cycles to purchase, and working on customers' cycles including full services to brake pad replacements.

June 2013 - Present: The Bolton Arms, Redmire, North Yorkshire. Bartender.

June 2016 - Present: The Three Horseshoes, Wensley, North Yorkshire Kitchen Assistant, Waiter and Bartender.

Skills gained from employment:

- · Communication and Organisational skills
- Customer service
- Handling money and numerical skills
- Working as part of a team and as an individual
- · Training new members of staff
- Offering specialist advice and completing stock takes

Work Experience

December 2018: Artificial Intelligence Lecture and Workshop

I was asked by my artificial intelligence lecturer, Dr Simon Lynch, to organise a lecture and workshop around the topic of artificial intelligence for groups of sixth formers. I was tasked with creating demonstrations of agent based models in NetLogo in addition to multiple programming exercises

September 2015 - Present: Student Representative for Computer Science

As a student representative at my University, I have been given the opportunity to report feedback from fellow students to help to improve aspects of my course. This position has enabled me to experience formal meetings with academic members of staff and speaking in public, whilst also allowing me to develop my listening skills.

Skills and Attributes

Technical Skills:

- **Programming Languages:** Java, C#, VB.NET, UiPath, NICE, NetLogo, Clojure, SQL, Python, Swift, HTML 5, CSS 3, Git
- IDE Tools: NetBeans, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, XCode NICE, UiPath, SSMS, Android Studio
- Databases: SQL Server, MS Access
- Other Software Tools: Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Publisher, Photoshop
- Operating Systems: Windows Vista/7/8.1/10, Linux(Ubuntu, CentOS, Fedora), Mac OS X
- Hardware: Experience building PC's and replacing components

Soft Skills:

- · Working with agile development methods
- Working as part of a Scrum team
- Presentational skills
- Client interaction

Other Skills:

Clean, full driving licence.

Interests

Travel:

- I enjoy travelling, learning about and participating in a variety of cultures.
- I have visited countries including, France, Holland and Switzerland along with experiencing famous attractions including the Large Hadron Collider at CERN in Geneva.

Cycling:

- I have custom built my own cycles and competed in many different disciplines of cycling from Downhill racing to BMX.
- I have won a variety of awards for my participation in competitive motorcycle trials.

Computer Hardware:

I have a keen interest in computer hardware and have built many custom computers.